<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>btrdb on NI4AI Blog</title>
    <link>http://blog.ni4ai.org/tags/btrdb/</link>
    <description>Recent content in btrdb on NI4AI Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 00:02:12 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://blog.ni4ai.org/tags/btrdb/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Voltage Sag Safari: Exploring Voltage Sags with BTrDB</title>
      <link>http://blog.ni4ai.org/post/2020-04-15-voltage-sags/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 00:02:12 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.ni4ai.org/post/2020-04-15-voltage-sags/</guid>
      <description>Voltage sags are significant transient dips in the network voltage, lasting for less than a cycle to several seconds. They can be caused by faults, motor starts, equipment misoperation, or fast reclosing operation of circuit breakers and are relatively common events in distribution and transmission networks. Large, long, or frequent voltage sags can be problematic for utilities, as they can cause sensitive loads to turn off, motors to stall, or solar photovoltaic inverters to trip offline.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunshine uPMU Data</title>
      <link>http://blog.ni4ai.org/post/2020-04-08-sunshine-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 12:30:37 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.ni4ai.org/post/2020-04-08-sunshine-data/</guid>
      <description>The primary synchrophasor dataset that is currently available in the NI4AI platform is from 6 topologically related uPMUs measuring data intermittently from 2015-2017. The dataset was collected for academic power engineering research and has been anonymized to remove sensitive and location-specific information. Because it was the first dataset to be made public on the platform, we&amp;rsquo;ve named it the &amp;ldquo;sunshine&amp;rdquo; dataset and it can be found in the sunshine/ collection in the plotter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Memory Efficient BTrDB Queries: Part 2</title>
      <link>http://blog.ni4ai.org/post/2020-02-14-btrdb-queries-pt2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2020 16:55:21 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.ni4ai.org/post/2020-02-14-btrdb-queries-pt2/</guid>
      <description>In Part I we introduced the tree data structure and discussed the two main algorithms for traversing them: depth-first and breadth-first. It is highly recommended that you review that post if these concepts are new to you, as Part II will build on them with more complicated examples using the Berkeley Tree Database (BTrDB).
In this post we will review three multi-query approaches for memory safety. First, we will explore chunked queries that allow us to scan across the database, loading fixed size chunks of memory at a time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Memory Efficient BTrDB Queries: Part 1</title>
      <link>http://blog.ni4ai.org/post/2020-02-12-btrdb-queries-pt1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2020 10:20:38 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.ni4ai.org/post/2020-02-12-btrdb-queries-pt1/</guid>
      <description>The Berkeley Tree Database (BTrDB) provides effective distributed storage of dense scalar-valued telemetry data. It can store data with nanosecond precision, and it supports reading and writing more than 10 million points per second per node. As a result it is an excellent tool for analyzing historical high-frequency (usually 30-240 Hz) sensor readings that produce gigabytes of data an hour.
When working with such large amounts of data, it is important to conduct queries in a manner that efficiently utilizes the main memory of your machine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Training General Linear Models with the PredictiveGrid™</title>
      <link>http://blog.ni4ai.org/post/2020-02-04-linear-models-overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 16:46:23 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.ni4ai.org/post/2020-02-04-linear-models-overview/</guid>
      <description>Linear Modeling Process Overview BTrDB (the Berkeley Tree Database) is the core of the PredictiveGrid™ and implements a time series database API that is extremely effective for distributed analytics including the training of general linear models. To efficiently distribute storage to accommodate a high rate of data ingest from multiple sensors, data is stored in independent streams. As a result, univariate forecasting models are very easy to construct since, unlike querying a database table, queries are directly to measurement streams.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BTrDB Explained</title>
      <link>http://blog.ni4ai.org/post/2019-12-12-btrdb-explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2019 19:42:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.ni4ai.org/post/2019-12-12-btrdb-explained/</guid>
      <description>BTrDB is a next-gen timeseries database for high-precision, dense telemetry.
 The Berkeley Tree DataBase (BTrDB) is pronounced &amp;ldquo;Better DB&amp;quot;.
 Problem: Existing timeseries databases are poorly equipped for a new generation of ultra-fast sensor telemetry. Specifically, millions of high-precision power meters are to be deployed throughout the power grid to help analyze and prevent blackouts. Thus, new software must be built to facilitate the storage and analysis of its data.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>